Well, on that note, let me try and
thoroughly explain this
one is such a beast, too. Oh my gosh.
Good luck, Joel.
Yeah, I don't I don't know if I fully
understand this one, to be honest. We
should
We should have taken bets in advance.
Like, all right, how many out of how
many So, we each have five, right? How
many out of five are we going to be able
to successfully get a passing grade on?
So, I think I think I'm going to start
this one off with a song, Joel.
Oh, no.
We're going to get copyright strikes.
It's the most wonderful time Oh, now
we're definitely getting copyright
strikes.
It's the top 10 web hacking techniques
of 2023 by PortSwigger Research episode.
Oh, yeah.
It's going to be This is going to be a
good one. I'm really excited. Yeah,
dude, it is going to be a good one, but
let me say I am Well, before before I
talk about myself, where are you right
now, Joel? Cuz you look like you're in a
dungeon.
I basically am. I'm in in my parents'
basement. Unfinished basement. Yeah,
unfinished basement. This house is like
250 years old, so
it's it's like old school basement. Aw,
dude. But yeah, I
I drove from California to
the East Coast to I guess I'll
Should I say which state?
You can leave that out for now.
I'll say East Coast. Yeah, but yeah, I'm
moving into a new house. We're closing
soon, and
yeah, it's pretty exciting.
Super pumped.
Well, I I saw the the Zillow listing for
your house. It looks awesome, and soon
you'll be not in a dungeon, but in a
mansion.
Yes, yeah. Well, mansion is
Maybe maybe not, you know, just like
contrast contrast-erily.
They're going to They're going to think
I'm I'm loaded with bodies. It's all
from that, you know, critical thinking
money is what it is. Oh, yeah. Oh, yeah.
Yeah, I got mansion money now.
We're just We're just loaded from doing
this podcast.
Oh, man. Cool. Well, yeah, like you
said, dude, it's going to be one heck of
an episode. Essentially, what we tried
to do last year and what we're going to
attempt to do again this year is cover
all of the top 10 web hacking techniques
of 2023, um,
which PortSwigger releases. They do sort
of like a competition every year. And
you know, the community votes on the top
hacking techniques.
And all of these are amazing pieces of
research and are extremely technically
dense.
Um, and so for the past, I don't know,
it's probably taken me 10 hours or so to
read through everything and fully
understand and prepare a document and
that sort of thing. Um,
yeah, and and and so we're going to try
to condense it down to pretty much what
you need to know, the tricks and tips
and,
you know, assuming a base level
knowledge of,
uh,
you know, hacking techniques, what is
what are the things about these specific
pieces of research that stand out? Um,
and we'll try to condense that into into
one episode. Do you think we can do it,
Joel? I don't know.
Uh, we're going to we're going to try,
you know. This,
uh, yeah, I was reading through some of
these, and they are really really deep
reads. Um,
so, yeah, even if we explain it well, I
think
everybody should still probably go read
them all individually.
Yeah. Yeah, disclaimer, we are going to
skip number two.
.NET serialization What what is it
called? Exploiting hardened .NET
deserialization, cuz it is a 124-page
white paper
that
Justin sent me this document. He's like,
"Hey,
can you just like read through these and
make sure that they're like summarized?"
And so, I I picked the first one that's
assigned to me, and I open it up, and
it's a GitHub link to a PDF. And I was
like, "Oh,
you know, this this looks good." I
downloaded it, and I open it up, and
it's page one of 124. And I was like I
sent him a picture. I was like, "Did you
know that this is a 124-page white
paper?" And he was like, "Wait,
seriously?"
I did not know that. I did not know
that. So, you know, we're we're going to
skip that one, but I think, you know,
the rest of them we should be able to
speak to fairly well.
Um, so
Let's let's get into it, man. First up
is number one. We're going to start from
number one this year. I don't know. Did
we start from number 10 last year? I
feel like we did.
I don't know, but I'm going to do it in
whatever order it's in the doc, which I
think is the same order that's on the
the the post.
are. This is the the placing order. So,
number one, and it was kind of funny if
you actually click the link to to go and
look at the actual
PortSwigger Research, you know, the top
10 web hacking techniques of 2023
research, there's like a description for
each one of them. And number one,
obviously, James is the one that kind of
puts this on, James Kettle. And then he
said, you know, his one number one,
uh, as as it should, cuz it's amazing
research. And so, he says in the
beginning of the the description for
that, he says, "Well, this is awkward. I
always knew that there was a risk of
rating research when I also publish it
myself. And after 7 years, it finally
happened. I now have to declare that my
own research is the best."
James, we all knew your research was the
best. Your your research has always been
the best. It wasn't really a question.
No, really.
Kind of crazy. Um,
but yeah, so he released some research
this year, James did, James Kettle. And
he releases research every year, and I
always make a habit
I always make a habit of trying to read
it as soon as possible,
um, because
often times he's highlighting systemic
issues that can be exploited in lots of
different environments. Um, and so I I
always make a habit of reading this
right off the bat. So, I've I've read
through this multiple times before now.
This is my my third or fourth time
through it. Um, and this is a
particularly simple, to be perfectly
honest,
exploit that that James kind of came out
with this year. It It takes some uh,
pieces of research from two different
researchers and some of his own research
from the past, uh, combines it together
with some features of HTTP/2
and creates this super awesome
technique, which is like now the go-to
technique for, um,
for race conditioning,
uh, testing in the brow or in the in web
applications.
Um, have you have you seen it, Joel?
Have you read through this whole thing?
Well, yes, so interestingly, this
research is actually used in another one
of the top 10, um, Oh, really? uh,
vulnerability. Yeah, so so I'll I'll let
you cover it cuz I think it'll make the
the the other bug make a little more
sense. I I I I didn't get to the chance
to read through all of the ones that you
that you're
that we assigned to you. Um, so I'm
interested in hearing about it, too. But
essentially, to summarize this research,
um,
James figured out a way to abuse Nagle's
algorithm, which is sort of like a TCP
algorithm that, uh, is used in to
optimize TCP packets being sent, um, so
that there isn't like a bunch of TCP
metadata and then like one byte of data,
um, in conjunction with HTTP/2,
uh, in conjunction with the last byte
sync,
um,
sort of idea that he had from a couple
years back on getting, um, race
conditions to align. And essentially,
the the new thing is he utilizes HTTP/2,
which can send multiple,
um, uh, sort of HTTP requests streamed
together, um, in a single TCP packet.
Um, and then essentially, he only he
used In one TCP packet, he used he puts
the last byte and sometimes the, um, the
the last byte and the end stream, uh,
frame for the HTTP/2 sort of structure
um, in the same TCP packets for for a
bunch of different HTTP requests. So,
stream most of the body for all the HTTP
requests, save the last byte and the,
uh, end stream frame, um, and then send
those all at once, and that will
complete all of those HTTP requests all
at once, and essentially get your,
uh, hit times for these requests down to
sub-1 millisecond, allowing for very
effective race conditions to be
achieved.
Amazing technique. Absolutely
mind-boggling.
Super super interesting. Uh,
I misspoke.
This is a different piece of Albino Wax
research.
Oh, really?
Yeah, no, so
uh, yeah, well, I'll I'll explain my
other one
when I get to there. But yeah, no, this
is
I mean,
one of the things that I really love
about James' research is that he
approaches things from like a
fundamental level, right? He's like For
a long time, he was looking at like, you
know, HTTP smuggling and desyncing and
all that kind of stuff and like
attacking like the layer, what is it,
layer three, layer four,
the, you know, level, you know, HTTP
servers and all that kind of stuff. And
then,
now he's he's at like TCP layer.
So so close to like I mean, next the
next Albino Wax,
you know, research is going to be
plugging in an Ethernet He's going to be
like And that's the MAC address level
now.
I do like that how he approaches it from
a holistic perspective.
And I also think that this specific
write-up, so the the concept is pretty
pretty simple, you know, group the last
byte for a bunch of HTTP requests into
one TCP packet, um, you know, with all
this data being sent over HTTP/2. So,
that's really cool.
And in the write-up, he does a really a
really good job of making the algorithm
seem really simple. And he actually
condenses it down to just a couple
bullet points. So, I'm just going to
read it word for word here. He says,
um,
excuse me.
First, pre-send the bulk of each
request. If the request has no body,
send all the headers and don't set the
end stream flag. Sorry, flag. I I said
frame, but it's flag. And withhold an
empty data frame with end stream set. If
the request has a body, so that that
that was was there's no body, then send
the headers and all the body except the
final byte. Withhold a data frame
containing the final byte, okay?
Um so that's all you've got to do. It's
really easy to implement in in various
uh different libraries as well. So, this
is something that I really really like
Kido to implement. Um or once we get a
uh sort of plug in extensibility piece
of Kido, uh
I will really be looking forward to
using this because I know Burp has a a
feature now where you can group a bunch
of tabs in repeater into a group and
then you can right click and hit send in
parallel and it will actually use the
single packet methodology
to send
all of those together and synchronize
them. And I just think that's such a
beautiful simple way to do race
conditioning.
Yeah. Yeah, exactly. Maybe I Maybe Maybe
this is somewhat related then because
the uh the the I'll talk about this book
now. Are you Are you uh Yeah, that's
that's about it for this one. I mean,
just the takeaways for this one I just
want to highlight again is
understanding, you know, this how it
works, right? With the HTTP/2 and
um sort of including only that last byte
as well as the end stream
um flag as well. And then also just
being able to do this in Burp, right? Um
with with the uh send in parallel. Those
are the main sort of takeaways for this
one in a allow you to also getting down
to one 1 ms sort of time, which would
really really make And this is also no
network jitter affects this because it's
all hitting the server at the same time,
which is uh just revolutionary. So,
yeah, that's my I've said my piece now.
Where did you want to go with that next,
Joel? Okay, so what I was going to say
is um you know, so this next book also
This is a number two. Sorry.
Oh my gosh, so we're going to jump
around. Okay, what number is this?
Number Well, number two was uh the
124-page white paper.
Okay, okay, okay. dot net serialization.
So,
uh
I will jump around. I'm going to jump to
number eight, uh which is the from
Akamai to F5 to H to
Um now this is a really really cool bug.
Um
it's uh it's one of those bugs that you
read through and you're like, "Wow, this
sounds almost too simple to be true."
Um because essentially it is like
textbook HTTP request smuggling.
Um they they were just doing a normal
pen test. They were, you know, looking
at this target. At the end of their
test, they ran an HTTP HTTP smuggler
scan through Burp and uh it came back
with a bunch of findings. They're like,
"Oh, that's kind of weird. Uh you know,
the it looks like the trace method is uh
is being like processed by this back-end
server." Um and there were a lot of
references to Akamai and Akamai edge
servers.
And so, he did a bunch more testing and
he noticed that indeed you there was,
you know, a specific gadget that he was
able to put together that you could um
put HTTP request smuggling through the
Akamai edge directly like directly
attacking the Akamai edge itself instead
of like the customer servers underneath,
but you would have the ability to to
attack, you know, other proxies and
stuff, right? And so,
um because there are so many different
possibilities, he initially found like
right away 25% of
the global caches could be poisoned
through cache poisoning directly through
the HTTP smuggling. So, HTTP request
smuggling into the Akamai edge servers
and then from there, you can smuggle
whatever you want. You can poison the
cache of internal servers, the Akamai
cache,
all that kind of stuff. Uh but then he
also realized like, "Oh, well, I mean,
Big-IP by F5, this is vulnerable to
uh you know, cache poisoning as well. A
lot of people use Big-IP especially
behind Akamai." So, he started scanning
for through uh Akamai using his
vulnerability to find other Big-IP
servers and sure enough like, you know,
3/4 of the Big-IP uh servers were also
vulnerable to cache poisoning.
So,
he's going through, he's farming, he's
submitting a bunch of reports, he's
getting 3, 4,000, you know, per report.
He's got like 20, 30 of these reports.
Look at this. And then he's like he's
looking through his his callbacks and
he's like, "Huh, that What is this like
weird off callback?" And he realizes
that there's this like NTLM off over
HTTP thing that exists for like Office
365 and a bunch of other things.
And uh as it turns out, you can also use
that to steal NTLM hashes. So, he was
able to through the Akamai edge into
Big-IP F5 Big-IP
poison the NTLM cache to get NTLM tokens
back and, you know, full off takeover,
you know, full arbitrary redirects
through cache poisoning.
Oh my gosh, yeah. I'm looking at this at
the end here. They just got like a bunch
of NTLM hashes just pouring in through
via via responder. He He's using the
tangent, it looks like. Wow, I wonder I
wonder why
Oh, this is
interesting here. So, what Why were they
reaching out to off in the first place?
Something super weird is going on here
with Microsoft
stuff.
Yeah, I have a feeling it's because of
the like weird redirect stuff that he
was testing out where he realized that
he would because he could cache poison,
he could basically arbitrarily redirect
people
from whatever to wherever.
um you know, customer logins or what
like an- anything you could put them
anywhere. And so, I think he was just
redirecting a bunch of stuff and started
to notice
uh that
you know,
he was getting these
these Microsoft
uh logins.
Request smuggling is such a crazy
vulnerability cuz you just start seeing
traffic from other people's like
sessions and stuff like that. And yeah,
I I I hadn't even thought about um sort
of
uh putting that together with like any
sort of NTLM-based auth because yeah,
there there are mechanisms for that in
in Microsoft environment. That is really
cool, man. What a What a cool way to
depends on the organ and, you know, how
they set it up, but yeah, I mean, this
was such a such a cool and I liked how
he was able to scale it, you know, like
that I find that's kind of challenging
for me like when I find something, I
usually rely on somebody else to help me
scale it, but being able to sort of like
identify that this is a widespread issue
and scale yourself is is pretty awesome.
Yeah, dude, that's sick. I'm definitely
going to go back and and redo this one a
little bit more. I feel like HTTP
request smuggling is like one of those
things that there are a couple people
that are really good at it and and that
like it shows up almost every live
hacking event still, too. You know,
somebody gets like some massive crit
from HTTP request smuggling. And it's
not like the normal the normal like big
crit players normally.
Uh it's like these people that are are
really good specifically at request
smuggling. So, I think that's one of the
things that I need to sit down and sort
of deep dive over the next, I don't
know, couple months and try to try to
understand that a little bit better. I
found it a couple times, but mostly just
relying on Burp and its scanner to tell
me when, "Hey, there might be something
funky going on here."
Yeah, same. I I feel like it's one of
those things I've exploited maybe like a
handful times, but I'd like to get a lot
better at it.
Yeah.
All righty, let's uh let's jump to to
number
I guess So, that was number eight. All
right, Joel.
Yeah, sorry.
Thanks Thanks for that, Joel. Now I'm
going to I'm going to have to go ahead
and uh I'm going to have to go in here
and
We'll go back in order a little bit.
strike Okay. I'm going to talk, you
strike through number eight and number
one on our list so that I I know which
ones we've actually done.
Um
and I'll jump down. So, like we
mentioned, we're skipping number two,
dot net deserialization, cuz it's it's
very long and we didn't have time to
prep it.
Um
and we're going to jump right to SMTP
smuggling, okay? And I thought this
write-up was was very funny. Uh it's
number three in in top web hacking
techniques of 2023.
And and there's a a quote from this uh
uh
write-up that says literally, quote,
"Since this blog post is about SMT
smuggling and doesn't have anything to
do with web applications,
dot dot dot dot." And I'm like, "Why is
this in the 2023 top web hacking
techniques if it doesn't even have
anything to do with web applications?"
Which is true, it doesn't. Um so, the
the rest of the write-up proceeded to
explain a bunch of SMTP um security
mechanisms and it does a really good job
of uh
like starting from zero um because a lot
of people that are reading this, or at
least for me as web hacker, aren't
familiar with the SMTP protocol super
in-depth. So, they give a nice summary
of SPF, which is um
essentially in place to validate what IP
addresses and domains are allowed to
send mail for a certain domain.
They They talk about DKIM, um which is
uh providing a signature for the body so
it isn't tampered, also validated over
TXT record
um by DNS. And then also DMARC. And
DMARC is the one that's really doing a
lot of the heavy lifting here because um
SMTP
uh protocol has two sort of from fields,
right? There's the mail from field,
which is sort of a part of the SMTP
metadata or the the commands that are
being sent to the SMTP server when data
is being transmitted. And then there's
like the message data from field, which
is
like a different from field. So, often
something that a technique that's used
to spoof is having the mail from being
different from the actual message data
from. Um and DMARC sort of solves that
issue by comparing SPF, DKIM, and the
from um in the actual body of the
message um to ensure alignment and that
sort of thing. Um and And this
technique, so it's called SMTP smuggling
and the reason for that is the guy sort
of took inspiration from James Kettle's
uh HTTP smuggling research and said,
"Hey, how can I apply some of these
things to SMTP?"
And the
the sort of data end indicator in SMTP
is
normally /r/n. /r/n,
right? So he's like, "Okay, I wonder
what we can do to kind of work around
that."
And so eventually what he ends up doing
is finding that some servers will accept
/n. /n
or /r. /r
as the terminator for a specific
message, right? piece of message data
and he can use that difference along
with some
I guess binary data encoding stuff on
some servers
um
to essentially create a mismatch between
the relaying SMTP server
the one that's sending the message the
one that the SPF record points to and
the SMTP server that receives the
message
and because you know all of this
authentication is happening on the other
side of this you
know you're you're essentially
taking advantage of a mismatch between
the relaying server which is allowed to
send mail for like something like
outlook.com, right? Some some big
domain you know that input is trusted so
I when I was looking at it it kind of
reminded me of a sort of a mix of SSRF
because it's taking advantage of what
that server's authority is, right? And
that server's position as a trusted
entity to send mail
and HTTP request smuggling
to send mail from pretty much any domain
which is which was totally badass but
not necessarily related to web hacking.
Yeah, not not quite web hacking.
Right. But that I mean now I'm thinking
like you know here we are leaking NTLM
hashes over HTTP so
you know maybe maybe it is possible
somehow or some way maybe there's some
some proxy server that will allow you to
send SMTP or something.
Yeah. So
so sort of big takeaways for this one
kind of understanding and applying HTTP
smuggling methodology where does the
data part of the transmission stop and
how can I get a mismatch between two
different entities on that?
That's one big thing.
And I also just really like the
concept of applying HTTP vulnerabilities
to different protocols that might have
similar functionality.
So I'm sure that there's other protocols
out there that could benefit from HTTP
smuggling esque
sort of vulnerabilities
and I I think we could definitely see
some cool research coming out like that
in the future.
Yeah, you know it it makes me think
especially like how what this looks like
on like code analysis side cuz that's I
feel like that's one aspect that I
haven't really seen covered like a lot
of this seems to be very very black box
approach like almost like
there's some weird magic that goes on
when I send all these requests in a
certain way and it just kind of works
this way but I'm more curious like why
like why does it work that like where
you know and is this like a pattern
because to some extent you know this
this sort of behavior is a pattern where
you can
you know basically like trigger it I
mean we've seen it as well like
we can sort of tangentially talk about
this, right? But like the bug that we
found
in LA
which you know uses like line
termination stuff or like you know how
how it's basically parsing like where
the end of things happen.
Yeah. Um you know and and and and that
sort of
you know weirdness with and the
inconsistencies between like one one way
of parsing and another way of parsing it
so I'm really really curious how this
kind of stuff like looks from source
code and if there's some way that we
could maybe scan for that.
For sure it's just kind of crazy to me
as well that you know all these
protocols have to be able to convey
arbitrary data, right? Like I need to be
able to send an email to you saying,
"Hey, SMTP ends with
you know
new line dot new line, right?" And then
that that new line dot new line has to
be included in the SMTP message that's
sent but also is the terminator you know
and so there's sort of like that data in
inception of sorts that of sorts that
happens
and when when delimiters like that are
used I think there's there's room for
for problems. I I have a zero day in an
a
CSS via JS library right now that
essentially dynamically creates CSS
rules and then inserts them into the DOM
and when it does that it it breaks on a
specific character
character sequence and if you take that
character sequence and you stick it in a
content attribute in inside CSS
which allows for strings, right? But by
nature
then it will split on that instead and
allow you to get arbitrary CSS injection
and will even allow for you to do like
what is it cyclical input chaining where
you can import other CSS um
style sheets from a a different server
and and that uses the same thing as like
there's some delimiter can we inject
that delimiter or can we find some other
similar delimiter that some parsers will
recognize as the delimiter itself?
Right. Any sort of normalization
anything like that?
Exactly. Exactly. Super cool. You know
the super This is one of the things that
that's really nice about doing a podcast
Joel is like you know we often have to
look at all this stuff
and think
what what
what sort of high level principles what
kind of overarching things can we
draw out from this research and apply to
other areas when we're talking about it
on the pod
and I think just having the ability to
or having to develop the ability by
reading it over and over and over again
to talk about it and then pull out those
principles is definitely making me a
better hacker every day. I I can I can
feel it.
Yeah. Yeah, I mean same dude it's I mean
because it requires some level of
stepping back. I mean we could have gone
through and read these line by line but
it wouldn't you know then the reader or
listener has to do what we're doing
there and so
Exactly.
you know it
it's nice to sort of get the those brain
juices flowing and make make you're
making me think you know on a Monday.
Yeah, man it it definitely is it
definitely is tricky and you you know
you you know what they say they can't if
you can't teach it you probably don't
understand it thoroughly so hopefully we
can hopefully we can understand all this
stuff thoroughly.
All right. Well on that note let me try
and thoroughly explain this
one is such a beast too. Oh my gosh.
Good luck Joel.
Yeah. I don't I don't know if I fully
understand this one to be honest.
have taken bets in advance like all
right how many out of how many so we
each have five, right? How many out of
five are we going to be able to
successfully get a passing grade on like
I'm only kidding.
All right. Okay so so this one was
really really cool. This one what was
the title? It was titled PHP filter
chains file read from error based
Oracle.
Okay.
So
to start with an error based Oracle is
essentially
you know similar to a SQL injection
where
you know an error based injection
basically you're triggering some sort of
error and using that as a way to
identify that something is happening or
not happening.
So there's this concept in PHP where
where there's the PHP protocol like PHP
colon slash slash and then there's all
these different attributes that you can
put after it and one of them is filter
and you can actually chain these things
together so there's all these different
filters that are built in to PHP that
you can combine
in sequence to do all sorts of really
really interesting things. You know
there's
rot13 for like shifting characters.
There's UTF-8 encoding Unicode encoding
and the encodings are really a big part
of this. You can do basic for
encode decode tons and tons of things.
Now there's a few a few key different
like filter attributes basically that
this this researcher used
and it mainly relies on this UCS-4
encoding. Now when you do this UCS-4
encoding it basically pads out each byte
into multiple bytes because there's more
bytes needed for each encoding of every
single character
and by doing that over and over and over
again you can essentially grow the input
to such a large output that it creates a
memory overflow and throws an error,
right? So there's our error.
No way. You're kidding me, man.
So so that's what is at the end of the
chain, right? And then the goal is how
do I make this thing exit early in a
predictable way so that if it exits
early I know it's one thing if it throws
an error I know it's another thing and
that is the Oracle itself. So you you
can use this
dechunk which is really designed to
parse chunks of you know chunk chunk
encoded data CRLF
you know ended data and the first
character is intended to be the length
of that chunk and so it will parse it as
a hex character and so if the first
character is a hex then it says, "Okay,
that's the length." and then it looks
for a CRLF after it. If it doesn't find
a CRLF it bails out so it doesn't throw
an error.
No way. Now you know whether or not it's
a hex character but you don't know which
hex character. So then there's another
encoding that you can do this this IBM
930 or or it's CP930
encoding and every time you encode it
the way that this encoding works is that
it it actually shifts the alphabet over
by like one so like an A would be hex 61
but in this encoding it's actually hex
and so it
they you can do this over and over
again. So, say you shift it one time and
nothing happens, then you shift it two
times, nothing happens, shift it three
times, nothing happens, shift it four
times, it crashes. Well, now you know
what the shift is so that you can go
backwards and you can figure out what
each character is
and then you can do stuff like ROT13 to
rotate them to get them into a known
range or you can do
the byte order mark encoding so that it
goes backwards instead of forwards so
you can read from the end instead of the
beginning.
I mean, it's such a such a cool attack
and you can
as I said, you can chain these things
together. So,
he has this code that basically
generates this massive long chain of all
these different PHP filters in order
that do all sorts of different shifting
and byte offsetting encoding and
decoding and all this stuff to leak one
character at a time
an arbitrary file and there's so much
impact. There's a ton of different PHP
attribute
attributes that are affected by this.
Um you can use it for
a ton of different functions fget fgetc
f open
parse ini file hash file
PHP standard in PHP standard out PHP
memory.
I mean, it's it's really really
interesting and it's one of those things
they highlighted a little bit in the
research but
like these many of these filters exist
but are not well documented on how they
work. Um like the dechunk filter which
is used to parse these these these
content transfer encoding chunks. It's
like written in C and it's like in the
source code but there's not really very
good clear documentation on how this
stuff actually works. So, it's just such
a really really cool
use of the technology and
one really fun thing is that at the very
beginning of this blog post
it's it says this attack method was
first disclosed during the DownUnder CTF
2017. It all came from a CTF and
I don't think anybody actually solved
it.
Yeah, nobody solved it.
Yeah, but basically the whole challenge
was just a file call on a post
parameter. So, you can provide it an
arbitrary input and it gets fed into the
file function in PHP. That's it. It
doesn't echo it. It doesn't do anything.
It just
calls it.
Using this, right, as an error-based
oracle, you could character by character
have read through the whole file.
No way, dude. That is like
So, I I just want to I just want to
specify, Joel, I told you before this
episode that I had read this. I did not
read this. This was something very
different from what I read. So,
Synacktive, the people that did this um
that wrote this up also did another
article called PHP filter chains and
what it is or what it is and how to use
it. Okay?
was the precursor to this one. Yeah, it
was and my mind was already blown blown
at the precursor and essentially what
the precursor does is gives you a script
essentially to generate arbitrary
content for like essentially
include-based stuff, right? So, if you
if you needed to you no longer need to
actually if you have a PHP include, you
don't need a file upload anymore
to get RCE from an LFI.
You can just use this file or this PHP
scheme with all these different filters
to generate arbitrary data which then
gets, you know, read and generates PHP
functions which is nuts. Um it's so
cool.
And I thought that was crazy and now
they've got this other thing where
they're like literally doing 16
different ways of leaking data like by
the byte which is
absolutely nuts, man. So, this is this
is so cool to see but I don't know, man.
I mean, I'm sure this has real-world
application where people will use this
to actually leak files but like this is
just the most CTF
thing I've ever seen in my life. So,
I I love it. It's it's almost like the
balance between like a CTF and code golf
where Yeah. Like it seems so simple and
you're like, okay, something there's got
to be some weird functionality here and
I love thinking about problem problems
in that way even if it's not a CTF
problem cuz it really makes you think
creatively about like, okay, let's
imagine this is vulnerable.
How? You know, what what are the
mechanisms? What is what's every single
lever I can pull and let me go through
every single one and and figure out what
I can exploit.
Yeah, and I'm I'm looking right now at
this exploitation
video.
I I just kind of got like
nerd sniped and it's fast, too. It's not
it's not particularly slow. You know, I
thought it'd be like, you know, try like
160 requests or whatever for one, you
know,
byte but it's it's pretty fast, too,
which is
very impressive.
Um
wow, what a piece of research. Man, you
got so many of the You got so many cool
ones. Now I got to
I'm sure they're all cool, you know, I
got to go and read them all
but that that one's definitely I'm going
to go back and reread that one. Um
although I probably should probably go
back and reread it next time I've got an
LFI because I'm definitely not going to
remember any of that [__] the next time
that I
about WordPress volts especially and
and the impact there. I've had an LFI on
WordPress stuff in the past
year for sure
actually in the past 3 months. But I
think actually something interesting is
going on with PHP 8. I believe PHP 8
doesn't allow you to do
the PHP scheme anymore for Ooh. like a
certain number of calls. Like I want to
say like fstat-
based calls, I think. So, like file
exists and that sort of thing. Um or
stat-based calls. Um
so, that's something to look up as well.
All right, man. Number four on the list
done. We're making progress. We're
pushing through.
Um next one on the list is HTTP parser
inconsistencies and I actually super
loved this research. I've tweeted about
this research before
you know, it got
put on the list here. But
this is such a a great example of just
like really quality
high quality lee conducted research.
What what am I trying to say?
The quality of this research is very
high in the way that they've conducted
it.
And there's a a bunch of different
backends that essentially they've
compared with how Nginx in particular
parses routes. And they provided
vulnerable configuration specifically
based off of the trim or strip
functionality associated with these
languages. So, essentially what kind of
characters like a new line character
like, you know, white space characters,
non-displayed characters, that sort of
thing can you append at the end or at
some spot in a route that will make it
um
not match a
Nginx rule or match an Nginx rule and
still match a route on the on the back
side. So, let's say you've got sort of
like a
a blacklist on the front end for
you know, Nginx and you you want to
access an admin route on the back end.
So, that's the whole scenario they set
up here. They set up like just like a
slash admin route or whatever that just
says admin. And it's a They've got an
Nginx route on the front end that just
says deny admin.
And then they get access to that by
adding
these various characters. So, I'll just
kind of read through these really
quickly um
to give you guys an idea for the various
languages.
And hopefully you'll go and document
these
yourself so that you, you know, when you
see the various server headers
pertaining to these various
technologies, you'll understand what
kind of inconsistencies could be in
place with Nginx in those backends. So,
um first up was
was Node.js and there is a bypass there
are many bypasses for Node.js when it
comes to Nginx
reverse proxy sort of
um
I guess blocking or
blocking a specific route.
The the one that works in the most
versions is the backslash x0
character.
So, that that code point. And that works
in versions 1.16
through 1.22.
Um and but there's also other ones such
as the hex 09 and 0c characters that get
stripped out by
Node's trim function and does
they don't get stripped out by Nginx on
the front end. So, Nginx assumes it's a
different route whereas Node understands
that it's that once it's trimmed, this
is actually just the slash admin route.
Yeah, and
I just I'll interrupt for a second. I
just love this
aspect of hacking where it's like
so often when you're testing these types
of things, you're putting like dot dot
slashes or percent zero a or backslash n
or but you're not actually
trying the character itself. And this is
this is like the the cool step where
it's like an actual, you know, like
Mhm. x0. Like you know, this weird
hidden like non-printable character that
is getting sent through and parsed
weirdly. Yeah.
Now, it
it is really good stuff and it's odd to
me and I I haven't taken the time to
dive deep and understand why each one of
these specific characters is a part of
the various languages
you know, trim or strip functionalities.
But it's kind of odd that this is so
hard. Like why can't we just
say, okay, white space is a space and a
tab and a new line, you know, and the
answer to that is because there's so
much variance in the specs and and stuff
like that but
it's just something that seems like it
shouldn't be that hard, but is actually
very hard, and that margin is where we
live, Joel. That margin is is where we
make our money.
the margins. Exactly. So,
cool takeaways for this one, you know,
make sure you're trying all of these
sort of hexadecimal code points, which
obviously correlates to various ASCII
characters. Um
I guess maybe not be within the ASCII
range. Uh but these are all very cool to
to try out. And essentially what we need
to be able to do is identify, hey,
there's Nginx plus some backend, where
the incompatibilities there. Um so, the
the ones that they've talked about here
are Node, specific Node versions, Flask,
Spring Boot, um PHP,
uh and I think that was it. And they
also talked about some stuff with um
with AWS
WAF in particular, which was super
weird, okay? So, I'll I'll deviate from
that whole um strip and trim
uh functionality there to bypass uh
various Nginx uh block blocking rules,
and actually talk about this this other
sort of like
extra that they kind of threw into this
write-up, which is essentially like
apparently some backends parse
line folding in headers
as a thing. So, essentially you have an
HTTP header, right? So, X colon bloody
bloody blah rn, right? And
then if the next line starts with a tab
character,
then it assumes that that that is a
continuation of the previous line.
And is is actually a part of the
character that's above it. So, in the
write-up they actually found a way to
bypass
the
um
Amazon WAF using this. But I just
thought that that was a weird thing to
actually have some languages parse.
Like, why are we line wrapping HTTP
headers at the protocol level? Like,
what is going on here?
It's so weird. It's so weird. And um
you know, I will say it sort of as an
overall overarching theme across these
top 10, I don't recall if it was
pulled out as sort of a conclusion
within the article itself, but what I've
noticed a lot is it's a lot of like
parsing bugs lately, where
Yeah. these aren't like these aren't
anything like it's not like we're even
talking about new protocols here or
anything, right? We're talking about
HTTP, we're talking about um
you know, SMTP, sure.
Again, old protocol.
But it's not like Protobuf or or or some
new technology or anything that's
causing this. These are all like
existing proto- existing protocols and
technologies that are very widely used,
but
just have some fundamental issues
depending on the implementation. Um and
a lot of it also reminds me of the
Orange research that we talked about um
not too long ago about the
Legendary stuff. Yeah, the HTTP parser
stuff in the Nginx
um you know, parser bugs with semicolons
and dot dot slashes and all that kind of
stuff.
Yeah, there's there's there's always
going to be those sort of bugs, and it
kind of goes back to what we were
talking about last week, which which is
like context, understanding the context
is king in in all of these scenarios,
really, because almost all of web
vulnerabilities uh I'm sure there's cut
and dry access controls and stuff like
that, but almost all web vulnerabilities
originate from some sort of
misunderstanding or um misconstruing of
context and what data is to be
interpreted in what context. Um Or
assumptions.
Yeah, or assumptions on that, exactly.
Um and and so, let me see. I think I
thought there was one more little
takeaway from this one that I wanted to
mention. Oh, yeah, the other cool thing
that they kind of mentioned within this
research as well was various backends
have a different way of parsing um
the
So, you know, when you do an HTTP
request, it's like get or post or
whatever, and then the space, and then
normally , and then it provides
the path, right? Mhm.
Um
some backends parse
that path piece differently
when the first character is not a a
slash. So, some people will let or some
some people
some backends will allow you to put an
at sign there, which is super helpful
for SSRF in some scenarios. Um some will
allow you to put a a semicolon there.
Some will allow you to put a and that's
often in the in sort of like the Spring
um environments where matrix parameters
are a thing. Um
and then some uh I want to say the was
it PHP environment? For some reason will
just let you put a an asterisk there,
which is real weird. Like, I don't even
know they didn't even mention in there
why they let you put an asterisk there,
but this is something to fuzz, for sure.
But another thing that I've seen is you
can put full HTTP URLs there as well.
That's for proxy syntax, I think, by
default.
HTTP
uh 0.9, I think, syntax.
Yeah, yeah, something like that. But it
also will will work in like, you know,
other HTTP versions. So, it all depends
on the implementation and and what they
choose to support. It's super super
weird. Backwards compatibility, another
thing that uh
makes us our living.
All right.
Um that's all I had for this one.
Uh you want to go ahead and take the
next one or or maybe we can tag team
that one since we uh we didn't get fully
through that one.
Yeah, so this one this one was from
a a
Kaspersky researcher, Sergey Bobrov. Um
he's a he's a really talented um
researcher, and he gave this
presentation at uh Off
Zone 2023.
Um and it's basically
talking about uh these HTTP request
splitting vulnerabilities, and
it all stems from these Nginx
misconfigurations, right? Just like
Orange research, just like
um you know, many other pieces of
research,
it's very easy to misconfigure things uh
without realizing it's misconfiguration.
Simply just by like trying to use, you
know, oh, I'm going to write this config
out. You and you put an extra character
or something, or you copy-pasted and you
didn't really know what it did, so you
just left it in there and it's the same
thing. You make ChatGPT write it.
Yeah, exactly. And it's like, here you
go. This this will work in all cases.
Um
and so, it's it's super super
interesting. There's
you know, the root of it is basically
uh this
uh
this regex, right? That's looking for
a slash
instead of just allowing all characters
to go through.
So, so yeah,
I brought it broke a couple things out
here into the doc, Joel, for this one.
And and that regex piece I think
requires a little bit nuance here. So,
essentially what what's crazy with this
is
may- maybe we'll we'll put this up on
the screen for those of you that are on
YouTube. Um
put on screen, please.
Put that one up. Um but essentially
there's there's this regex when you're
defining a location in Nginx reverse
proxy configurations. And if you use and
when I looked at this, it's just so
weird. So, if you use dot star, then
that's the safe configuration, you know,
for this, because it's not going to
allow you to inject
It does.
It's not going to let you inject like um
apparently these line break characters
that are going to make everything
terrible. But if you use an a um I guess
an exclusive range, so if you say square
bracket and then the upward carrot,
slash and then close close brackets,
you're saying, okay, allow every single
character except for the slash. And in
that scenario, that's a more permissive
definition actually than the dot
character, which is super weird, and
will allow you to inject new line
characters and line breaks, which will
allow you to just overwrite the whole
request, which is nuts to me.
It's super interesting cuz I want to say
that
I can't remember if if in regex by
default the dot
it's supposed to include white space,
but I don't know if it includes new
lines.
That's interesting. Unless you
explicitly have the like multi-line flag
on, right?
a good point. Yeah, that could be what
it was.
There's probably some weird
implementation issue here, because like
you said, one is like an exclude, like
an exclusive range, where it's like any
character that's not a slash, versus any
character that's a dot, which then gets
translated into A through Z, like any
character
maybe except new lines
um or or whatever. So, it's just like
it's it's such a weird nuance. Like, I
would have never expected that
those two things would be backwards.
And and just to be clear here, what
we're talking about is is matching the
location on an Nginx reverse proxy rule.
So, this is the definition for what
route you can hit and it will trigger a
certain block of code. Um and inside of
that there's regex to allow for things
like IDs and that sort of things to be
included. Um so, this is this is really
uh some some cool research, and it makes
me wish that I had the Nginx
configuration files for so many of these
targets that I work on that use Nginx.
So, it's like, man, I'm sure there's so
many like weird edge cases out there
that um that this could could cause. And
um and and the next one as well is is a
proxy pass based um
uh Nginx problem, which was actually
originating from some some research Fonz
did, of course, you know, years before
everyone else started thinking about it
in true blue Fonz style, um which most
of you guys have seen likely, where he
was proxy uh doing a proxy pass to
uh Amazon AWS, and was able to override
the host header, and since the the host
is actually um you know, since the
backend server is the same for all S3
buckets there, he could actually specify
his own bucket as the host header. It
would get virtual routed to his bucket,
and he was allowed to host any arbitrary
content on a website. Um so, that those
are the two sort of main techniques that
they mentioned in there for like how
this vulnerability could occur. And the
other thing that I thought was cool
here, Joel, was the detection methods
for this that they sort of outlined
because um,
I think this sort of bug is a little bit
tricky to understand and a little bit
tricky to find um, without source code
because you're not able to look at the
configuration file and say like, "Hey,
oh, that's one of those like commonly
known patterns that could result in HTTP
request splitting."
Um, and so they mentioned a couple
detection methods that could be helpful
for this. And the first one is simply
visiting
you know, site.com/ and then the path to
whatever your um, anticipated split um,
what am I trying to say there, Joel? The
the the place where you believe the
split may be occurring, right? Where the
Right. Right. The intended delimiter.
Exactly. Um, and then actually just
putting a space and an X there. So the
actual back-end HTTP request that gets
generated is
get or whatever / the path space X space
HTTP/1.1
or whatever, right? And that will result
in a 400 on the back-end and hopefully
that will bounce forward through the
reverse proxy and show you a 400. Um,
the uh, I'm sorry. That that will give
you a different error code.
That that's the differentiator. That has
to give you a different error code. So
if you put the space X in there, it
needs to give you some error code that's
not a 400. Then
Right. if instead you put space H,
nginx by default, it looks at that and
says, "Oh, that starts with an H. That's
them specifying the HTTP protocol."
That's so funny.
Right? So that's them saying that's the
beginning of HTTP/1.1,
right? Um, and then it will say, "Hey,
we're parsing the we're parsing the the
protocol here now. Oh, H is the
protocol. That's weird. That's not a
valid protocol.
Bam, 400, right? So this is a this is a
good way to tell whether you're actually
injecting into this sort of back-end um,
you're injecting into the actual syntax
of the HTTP request because space X
should give you some other error code
and space H because of that nginx sort
of tendency should give you a 400.
Yeah. Yeah. And then there's the
the one step further, right? Where
space HTTP and then you give it a, you
know, a a bad version like 13.37
and you finish the
CRLF at the end.
And it should say, you know, bad
protocol or something.
Exactly. That's for sure for sure then
you're you've got CRLF injection.
Yeah. So so the input there would be
space HTTP/
13.37,
of course. And then the new line
character. So we're completing that
first line of the HTTP request, right?
And then we'll, you know, add like the
NX header or something like that to
catch the remainder of the original HTTP
request. And then when the reverse proxy
tries to
communicate with the back-end server
like that, the back-end server's like,
"Wait, what the heck? I can't use HTTP
13.37. I I don't know that protocol."
Kicks back a 505. And 505 is a very rare
error code. I've only
I don't think I've ever seen it
actually.
Yeah. Um, and so if you are able to
trigger a 505, then you've certainly got
request splitting. So this could be
great for any of you people out there
that are doing mass scanning and want
some high signal um,
like scans to do for HTTP request
smuggling. Just what I would do is
actually, you know, run gau or something
like that. Take all of the paths that
come out of gau and then at that sort of
junction, at that each path level, then
put this this payload in there and then
look for detect off of 505s. And you
should have a pretty high signal
response for anything that that could be
vulnerable to HTTP request smuggling.
Yeah. Yeah, for sure. Super super
interesting. So I love those little
detection methods, you know, those easy
takeaways. And then if you see something
that's working, go back to that paper
and then start to read a little bit
deeper and then see how to exploit it.
Exactly, man.
Oh, man, the next one is so good.
Kinugawa Masato-san, thank you so much
for this for this write-up. Um,
I feel like nobody better could have
could have gotten the summary for this
one, so I'll let you go ahead.
it's it's great. And uh, I I So actually
at the beginning of of So number seven,
well, let me before I get ahead of
myself, let me talk about this what this
actually is. Number seven is how I
hacked Microsoft Teams and got 150k in
Pwn2Own by
uh, Masato Kinugawa. Um, and essentially
this write-up was great. And in the
beginning of it, he's like, "Hey, you
know, if you're interested about the
non-technical experience that I had with
Pwn2Own, here's a couple podcasts in
Japanese for you." So I've got those on
my list. I'm going to like put it on
like 0.75 speed and try to keep up with
these guys in in Japanese, but um,
I was able to fully parse through the
amazing write-up that he did. And wow,
there are some great takeaways from this
one. Um, so essentially what's happening
here is they're in an electron
environment hacking Microsoft Teams for
Pwn2Own.
And essentially he gives us some cool
takeaways on what to look for in an
electron environment. Pretty basic
stuff, stuff I've heard before, but
still helpful to review. So um,
whenever the browser window object is
instantiated in a um,
in an electron environment, um, there
will be some parameters that can be
passed into this. Three parameters of
interest in particular.
Node integration,
context isolation, and sandbox, okay?
And so what this is going to do, we'll
take those one by one. Node node
integration. If node integration is set
to true, then if you get XSS on this
target, um, this is the traditional
thing you kind of always hear about when
you when you get XSS in an in a electron
application, then you should just be
able to get RCE. Well, that's only true
if node integration is set to true
because then in that case you could
access the node node.js APIs directly
and do something like require and just
run, you know, whatever code and exec
your your calculator or whatever. But if
this is set to false, then you don't
have access to um, the node API and
you're not going to be able to um, get
RCE as easily. Unfortunately for uh,
um, Masato, then in the scenario, this
was actually set to false, so he had to
figure out some other way to get RCE
even if he had XSS.
Um,
the second one is
this is the second parameter that you
should be looking in into in sort of the
instantiation of the browser window
object, which is core to the electron
applications,
um, is the context isolation sort of
argument or boolean here. If if this is
set to false, then the context between
um,
the client-side JS and the JS that has
access to node APIs, um, is not actually
segmented.
Um, and and because of that, what you
can do is do prototype pollution. And
that's what he ended up doing later on
in this in this write-up is he
overwrites the function.call
um, definition prototype and was able to
snag access to
Pretty good one to override. It's
baller, I'm not going to lie.
Um, and was able to detect when the
correct function was being passed in and
get access to some stuff that he needed,
um, which is really cool. And the last
one is sandbox false or true. Um, that
one is
pretty clear for anyone who's ever
worked with Chrome. That's where the
Chrome's going to be running in a
sandbox. Um, if this is set to false,
then you've got a much easier time
exploiting Chrome-related bugs, um,
inside of an electron application. If
it's set to true, then you've got to
figure out how to escape the sandbox
even if you get like a Chrome-based RCE.
Um,
So so cool. So there's that, but dude,
this isn't even the craziest part, Joel.
This This is crazy, man. Okay. So I I
mean, I hear what you're saying. But I
think you're what's crazy. I'm not even
there yet.
Thank you for the information. Um, but
you've got to see the way he gets XSS on
this thing, man. So, you know, he's he's
participating in Pwn2Own.
Yeah.
Pwn2Own is a no user interaction event.
So you've got to pwn it without anyone
interacting with it essentially.
And essentially what he found was that
he could send a
message to a user over Microsoft Teams
and um,
he could specify some, you know, basic
markdown tags, right? Like bolding and
stuff like that.
And when you look at how that's
implemented,
you're able to implement a couple, you
know, HTML tags that are helpful. And he
he found a a
a white list for uh, class names
that can be specified on these uh,
you know, like the strong tag or
whatever, right? So now he's got like,
"Okay, I can specify some in one of
those those white lists had a star with
it." So it was like swift-whatever,
right? So now he can specify any class
name that starts with swift- which is
like, "How could this possibly be
helpful, right?" Like and I just I don't
understand how. And Joel, using that,
using not even arbitrary class name
injection,
he gets XSS,
which is just
absolutely
absolutely inspiring. Um,
and and and it's really um, a great
reason to look deep and understand how
this application,
how these applications are working and
every single bit of every single inch
you can take from the application might
be able to be used in an exploit.
That's so awesome. I mean, it it's got
to be like the perfect stars aligning
feeling where like he's looking through
he's like, "Oh, no way." Like
So so This exists? Exactly. So this is
how he did it, Joel.
Angular is being used in this
application, right? On the front end.
And there if you could specify an
arbitrary attribute in Angular, you
could specify the ng-init attribute,
which would allow you to run some code.
Pretty standard stuff with Angular, um
if you're familiar with it at all.
However, what I did not know is that the
ng-init attribute can also be specified
by a class attribute.
Which is super weird. Look at Look at
the Look at the screenshot in the doc,
dude.
Look Look what he's got here. He says,
"Any element ng-init equals expression,"
right? That's the one one we're familiar
with.
Any element class equals ng-init
uh
colon expression also allows you to just
run arbitrary JS code inside of the
class attribute for any
freaking
HTML tag.
That's so weird.
What?
Like it make Like why?
Like why does that work?
know, but it's Makes no sense.
context in which you can get XSS, which
is really cool.
Um so then he's able to use, you know,
constructor.constructor or whatever, the
the one of the classic ways to call
arbitrary JS code.
Um
and
get XSS. So now he's got XSS from when
from, you know, just sending a user a
message.
And that Now he's going to use the
context isolation to get RCE via that,
which was an absolutely crazy part of
this write-up and not particularly
generally applicable to most
environments. So I won't go too deep
into it, but essentially what he does is
gets access to this object um called IPC
renderer. And this is interprocess
communication renderer, and this allows
you to communicate between the main
process in in
in an Electron application, which is a
little bit more privileged, and the
renderer
process.
Um and essentially, using that
interprocess communication renderer
object, he's able to communicate with a
listener on that side of it's loaded up
that has a vulnerability in it and is
able to pop RCE
um and land that sweet sweet hunt-own
money.
Um
but biggest takeaways for me on this
one, make sure on Electron application
you're checking those three attributes,
node integration, context isolation,
sandbox. And then also, what the heck,
apparently you can get XSS via class
name injection.
Who knew?
Yeah, I mean, that is the like the last
thing I would have ever tried of all the
Like maybe if I was just broadly
scanning for
payloads in every attribute available on
on an element, maybe, but like that's
crazy.
truly given up.
Yeah.
The the the levels of desperation that
we go to
to pop XSS, man. Um
Okay, so Joel, you already covered
Akamai F5,
Um
Yes. which was number eight. Number
nine, I'll just kind of breeze through
really quickly. Um
And essentially, this is Cookie
Crumbles. This is a long academic paper
written in academic style with a bunch
of like, you know, special notation
where like, you know, why is this? And
it's like, why why are we do making this
so complicated?
Um
But I read it, and it was good, and
it had some cool some cool techniques in
it. Some things that weren't quite as
applicable
that they seemed to be excited about,
but I don't think had as as much
real-world application, but I pulled the
good bits out for you, and I'm going to
go ahead and tell you about them right
now. They tried to re- They tried to
rename CSRF to to CORF, which is a more
accurate sort of representation of most
of the
cross-site Typical lab environment.
request forgeries, I know.
No, nothing against the people I mean,
they wrote a great piece of research,
but um
that is the more specific name,
cross-origin request forgery. So if
you're one of those people that would
like to be a little bit more specific
with what they're talking about, um
uh you know, I think you could use
cross-site request forgery and
cross-origin request forgery um to
interchangeably to to be able to specify
the the various nuances of these
specific situations where you may be
same site, but different origin.
Um
and you know, so there's some nuances
with with regard to that regarding to
same-site cookies. So that's one one
little thing. Couple other things they
talked about, stuff we've talked about
on the pod before, clicky tossing, which
is essentially using
um the path attribute of a specific
cookie to override the value of a cookie
that's already in place. Um
we've talked about this before, but I'll
just provide a little refresher.
Cookies that are set, so let's say
you've got a cookie set gadget via an
XSS or something like that, you can make
your cookie prioritized in the user's
browser um if there's a cookie of the
same name by specifying a more specific
path. Um uh otherwise, it will default
to which one was created first. Um so
really helpful thing there. It doesn't
actually depend on which domain was
specified in the cookie at all, which
probably it should, but um uh you
probably should go by more specific
domain, but such is life.
The path specificity piece really
helpful for,
you know,
overriding for doing session fixation
and that sort of things. Like
when you need to get your cookie
prioritized over a cookie that may
already be set in the victim's browser.
Take a breath. Take a breather there.
Next one is cookie jar over-
That's 150 pages.
Yeah, what Dude,
Dude, I mean, how I mean, our notes from
this episode as well are like what,
eight pages long? All right, yeah, I
don't even know. I turned off the pages
cuz I didn't want to know.
nuts, man. Um and then the next thing
they talk about, cookie jar overflowing,
we talked about that. I've got an app
set up at apps.rennator.dev
that you can check out to see, you know,
how many cookies you need to overflow
your specific browser. Normally, it's
about 180. Um and another cool takeaway
is you can push out HTTP-only cookies
from the the cookie jar
with non-HTTP-only cookies. So
good to know.
Very interesting. The novel attacks from
this research, there were two.
Um and these have also been mentioned by
Ankur Sundara, whose uh write-up we
mentioned and will link in the
description
we mentioned in the past.
Um but essentially, these attacks are
surrounding nameless cookies
and how you can set a cookie that
doesn't have a name, and so it's set-
cookie colon equals something. And the
way that browsers handle that is really
really hecked up, and servers don't know
how to parse it, and everybody's like
screaming, and
it's it's bad.
And so if you think there's some sort of
weird nuance you can do with that,
that's a functionality that you're that
you should be aware of.
Unfortunately, uh most of the
applications of this from an attacking
perspective are overriding the __host
and __secure
prefixes to cookies, which are
essentially just um like
more secure versions of the cookie
attributes um
secure and setting the domain attribute.
Um
So
there's not a ton of of
uh application of these nameless
cookies, but it's still some nice quirk
to be aware of. And there's lots of
sort of misconfigurations and
misinterpretations of cookies
when those cookies' names starts with an
equal sign that they sort of documented
in this paper.
Um and and and I think that they
also listed a bunch of CVEs that they
found and got fixed in this paper, which
cool, you know, cuz we, you know,
you may be able to bypass those or use
them in an environment
that is like
when you're dealing with that sort of
older technology, but they're patched
now, so not a ton of super awesome
takeaways from from that from like a
sort of a methodology perspective.
Yeah. Yeah. Mm. But I do love that
little replacement. Like, you know, it's
just one of those gadgets you tuck tuck
in your back pocket, and and later when
when you need it in that one-off chance,
it'll be there when you need it.
Exactly. Exactly.
All right.
The next sort of novel attack that they
sort of mentioned here, um it is
various bypasses for __host, like I
mentioned before, in in a bunch of
different server-side parsing
environments, PHP, we all know the
thing. Well, maybe we don't all know.
It's pretty well known that PHP replaces
dots with underscores
and a couple other characters, I think,
as well, dashes included, with
underscores when they're populating
their uh infamous dollar sign underscore
get underscore dollar sign underscore
post dollar sign underscore cookie
objects. Um so that caused some problems
for essentially processing those cookies
as well. Um so be on the lookout for
those sort of discrepancies. Um
The last piece of helpful information
from this
write-up or from this research that I
was able to find was a pretty
well-documented description of various
CSRF protections. Um they they came
There was a couple far-fetched examples
where they were like, you know, "If
you're able to like set a cookie, and
there's like pre-session fixation, and
like
the generator for the CSRF token is
linked to like the pre-session, not the
actual session." It's like
There's some really odd stuff in there
that didn't seem quite as
applicable. Um
then, you know,
there were those, which was interesting,
but the one that I thought was most
helpful was they make a a description of
a common CSRF framework which I'm not
sure we've actually talked about here on
the pod which is called the double
submit pattern of CSRF protection, okay?
And essentially what this is is
the the application will set a cookie on
the user session that says CSRF token
equals XYZ, right? And then when you
send a request, you have to send in the
body CSRF token equals XYZ. And on the
server side, it will compare the cookie
that you sent and the cookie in the
request body and make sure that those
align and if it is, then it passed the
CSRF check. Um so this I've seen this
many times. I've bypassed this many
times. If there's a way for you to
fixate a session a session a CSRF token
and get your CSRF token prioritized,
right? Using the path methodology that
we mentioned before, you can fixate that
token, you know, maybe using a subdomain
and access has a subdomain or something
like that and get your token prioritized
and then
um send that value as a CSRF token
parameter in your post request or
whatever request to CSRF
um and that will result in a bypass of
CSRF protection. So that was something
that they documented really clearly that
I don't think we've talked about before,
so I figured I'd I'd mention that as
well as the last piece of information uh
in this Cookie Crumbles academic
research analysis.
Thank you very much.
That was that was a man, that was such a
dense one. It's Yeah. Uh it it sucks
because it's such awesome research, but
it's uh it's very difficult to like
get through it, you know? Like
if only these academics could figure out
how to write blogs. I know, man. I know.
And you know, I I I I hate
I hate to dislike it to be honest
because they're doing us a great service
in finding a bunch of really cool
things, but um yeah, it's so different
reading blogs versus reading academic
write-ups, so. But maybe that's my own
experience as well, you know? Maybe I
just need to read more academic papers.
As somebody who's written a couple
academic papers, it's uh
it's definitely a little song and dance
to to you know, for the whole process
and they could be simplified, I think.
Sure is, man. All right. Last one on the
list, EPP server takeover by our boy Sam
Curry.
Um let's go ahead and give a a um
analysis of this one.
Uh we'll talk about it and
uh close it out for this for this
episode. Um yeah, sure.
to go ahead and and take it? It's it's a
pretty straightforward XXE, I think, but
in just the most crazy critical piece of
environment ever.
Yeah, right. It's like extremely
extremely safe straightforward. So
there's this whole protocol called EPP.
It runs on port 700.
And it's an XML-based protocol and
literally like the most like open a
socket on port 700, send
the like
github.com
textbook example of of an XXE payload
and it's like full read of Etsy
password, you know what I It's like it's
it's really really like the most simple
XXE possible which is kind of terrifying
knowing that that is you know, was
running some core part of in internet
infrastructure for a very very long time
and it was just
widely vulnerable for a very very long
time.
Um but it's just one of those great
great examples of
you know, don't take anything for
granted, right? Maybe that's the
takeaway for this. It's like even if
it's a core technology, even if it's
something that seems really
straightforward, don't take that for
granted. It's probably vulnerable and
you should you should dig a little
deeper, right?
Absolutely. Every single thing today is
but you know, like fundamentally HTTP,
fundamentally SMTP, fundamentally EPP,
all the P's.
Yeah, everything. It's uh it's it's I
mean it's it's mind-boggling uh to think
uh how many things I've probably have
looked over just because I'm like that.
There's no way that's vulnerable. I'm
not going to spend time on that.
the other really cool thing that they
did here was actually understand uh they
they strayed outside of the realm of web
app security and they they went into
this, you know, odd protocol that's
running on on port 700 and sometimes the
dubs are there, you know?
Um and and so that's really that's
really impressive, I think. Um and and
and
I just this line who cracks me up, man.
He said you know, like you said, he like
it's the the same, you know, leak Etsy
password uh
sort of
default XXE payload that you see from
GitHub and he says, "Our proof of
concept was extremely effective."
And it's great. It was, dude. It was. It
was amazing. Um It's so awesome.
And it just goes to show that that
uh there are weak spots and those weak
spots are going to be the best spot to
get in because they got control of
how many I mean this is like 20
top-level domains
um Yeah, seriously.
from from this. And um the other thing
that I'll say here is that notice how
they they pivoted, right? You know? They
didn't just
uh take this XXE, they used it to grab
some some source code and parse out some
Java that was running in there and then
they found another LFI that allowed them
to get access to
Etsy shadow and somebody's private key
to actually log into the server which is
just so badass.
Which had backups of all the root zones
as well.
It's nuts, too, that how much of this
how much of this internet infrastructure
that we all rely on every day is like
just taped together with, you know,
already owned stuff. Yeah. Yeah.
Absolutely nuts, man.
Well, on that lovely uh optimistic note
Yeah, on that it's a wrap, right?
Anything else we got on on this one? I
think that was about it. We we actually
moved through this pretty quickly,
probably because we skipped the 124-page
.NET deserialization white paper.
Yeah, yeah, no kidding. Yeah, I
I mean it's still a really really
interesting paper. There's a bunch of
CVEs in that one as well and
I I'm for sure going to go circle back
on that one and and read through it a
little more closely, especially when I'm
testing on .NET stuff.
Absolutely.
Let let me ask you this, Joel.
Let's let's reorder them, okay? We'll
we'll we'll pull we'll pull the
the .NET deserialization one out cuz we
haven't, you know, done our our due
diligence on that one. But if we were to
go ahead and reorder this,
where would you put it?
Hm.
Okay, I think I would put
I would leave the state machine at the
top. That one's the most widely
impactful, I think, right? Yeah, yeah,
that's really cool fundamental like
research in my opinion.
Hm.
I think I would put
the HTTP request splitting, the HTTP
parser inconsistency, and the
Akamai F5. Those are all very very close
to me. I think I'd bundle them together
somewhere together.
Maybe not. Maybe like third place. I
think second third through sixth place.
Uh third place. Yeah, third through
sixth. Second place, hacking Microsoft
Teams.
Really? Uh I think so cuz that's such I
mean that's like
so crazy.
Uh or no, sorry. Second, EPP. Oh, I'm
I'm all out of order here now. Okay.
First place, stacking smashing the
stack. Okay, hold on. Hold on. Hold on.
Wait a sec. Wait a sec.
I'm going to I'm going to actually write
down Joel's list here. Okay. So smashing
smashing the state machine.
Not
the Yeah. There you go. That one. Yeah,
it's the state machine. Um
EPP, number two.
EPP.
Numbers three through six tied or tied
for third. Okay. So we've got parser
inconsistencies, okay.
And uh Akamai F5.
Parser splitting,
Akamai F5.
And then Okay.
Hacking Microsoft Teams.
Teams.
Okay.
Then
SMTP and Cookie Crumbles and filter
chains.
Filter chains is seven.
is I'm almost
tempted to put that a little lower, but
and then Cookie Crumbles and
SMTP.
SMTP. All right, dude. So you said
smashing the state machine, EPP, parser
inconsistencies, request splitting,
Akamai F5, Teams, filter chains, Cookie
Crumbles, SMTP
uh smuggling.
This is a very different order
than what I would do. The only one
probably that's similar is smashing the
state.
Okay.
Uh so I think I'm going to put mine at
smashing the state machine at the top
and the reason for that is that it's
very elegant research. The con he
explains it really well. The concept's
fairly simple. The implementation is
very clear and the implications are
giant for an underserved vulnerability
class. Um
Second for me, man,
I don't know. If if the filter chain
piece where you can just um generate
arbitrary content like generate like you
know, question mark PHP
you know, run PHP info or exec or
whatever.
If that's included,
which I think is extremely applicable
research, then I got to put I got to put
um filter chains at at number two.
Yeah, filter chains is one of those like
uh when I'm looking at my list, it
doesn't feel like number seven. I think
it's hard because
I mean it's somewhere in like three
through
three through three or four, I think.
Yeah, maybe I would put filter chains
above the three parsing ones after you
the EPP server. The EPP server for me is
like such a cool like fundamental like
internet core
infrastructure thing.
Um that that is so so crazy dangerous.
Um
and like so simple that it falls at
number two for me. But if it was like
you needed admin perms or something,
that would be higher on the list.
Yeah. I'm I'm seeing you type your list
out. So number one you've got smash
smashing the state machine.
Number two filter chains, three teams.
Uh
four
class splitting, five parser
inconsistencies, six cookie crumbles,
seven Akamai, which is interesting. Why
do you split the Akamai out from the
other
uh parser ones?
So I'm kind of doing it based off of
Dude, your
your laptop did the thing where it's
like where it did the thumbs up thing
again.
Did you see that?
Okay, no way because I'm not even using
the external Oh, it's on. I turned it
off.
gosh. What what is that thing, dude? It
pops up every couple videos.
thing called reactions and it's built
into Mac. I don't know
That's I thought it was only when I was
using my phone as an external camera.
weird. So
essentially what happens is he'll like
do a like a thumbs up on the screen or
something like that. And then
I'm like holding the mic like this and
it's And and it'll parse it as a thumbs
up and then it'll do like the thumbs up
emoji on the screen. I'm like, why are
you doing that? Um hopefully it's now
off for good. Man, now I'm going to have
to check that every single time.
Let me explain Let me explain my order
here, okay? So smashing the state
machine, obvious. Filter chains, I think
there's a big amount of implement
implications to this research. With
turning LFI to RCE, easy peasy. No, you
just eliminated a very strong
precondition, a very challenging
precondition to go to RCE. Um
which is awesome.
Um teams, I think
the the piece about just going from
class name to injection to XSS is just
stunning. Um so I I gave him credit for
that. And then also the technical
details, while we we didn't really cover
them here, of that interprocess
communication um technique that he used
there uh was was really really engaging
and I think um
highlights a knowledge of electron
internals that uh I hadn't really seen
showcased elsewhere. So I I I think that
that that was why I placed that at at
three.
Request smuggling and parser
inconsistencies,
very practical and very reproducible
in action
you know, actual environments. Reverse
proxies are used everywhere. Reverse
proxies are used to block off endpoints
everywhere. So I think um
uh
you know, these pieces of research are
very applicable.
Cookie crumbles, I actually put this at
six because I think that they're that
cookies are an underserved
piece of uh
sort of browser mechanics. They were
very much focused on, you know, back in
the days of like CSRF coming out and
that sort of thing. And um you know,
even just in like DOM XSS environment, I
feel like cookies are just kind of
underserved in general. Um and so I I've
I've got some extra love for cookies
lately. Um Akamai, I put that below to
break it out um
mostly because cookie crumbling didn't
really seem right at seven. Uh and the
Akamai one is a little bit less. It's
kind of kind of like a vuln story, less
of a like applicable research that can
be used in other environments. Um and
then I put the EPP stuff there as well
in eight because once again, it's a vuln
story. Um which is very engaging and
fascinating and I'm so glad I heard the
story, but um not necessarily
reproducible for us in other
environments. And then number nine, we
both put SMTP smuggling there because
it's not a web vulnerability.
Um so I think I think that's kind of
where my my top
top 10 or top nine, I guess, um lands on
the list. Uh pretty different from from
what they actually came up with.
Yeah, I mean it's super I
really threw I think I think yours are
your your ordering is probably a little
more level-headed than mine. I'm just
like
I'm like, this is these are cool bugs.
The more complicated, the better. Like
or the maybe the more the more the more
dumb easy, the better. I don't know. I
I I like there's something about that
like
really easy exploitation aspect that
really is is so fun. It's that like
just like, oh wow, this really simple
bug is like just out there.
Elegant exploits are are are very cool,
for sure.
All righty, man. Is that it for you? We
calling it a wrap there?
I think that's it. That's a wrap.
That's the pod.
That's pod. Peace. Peace.